Money_Prices = [1000, 2000, 3000, 5000, 10000, 20000, 40000, 80000, 160000, 320000, 640000, 1250000, 2500000, 5000000, 7500000, 10000000, 75000000]

Questions = [
    # Level 1
    [
        {
            'Question': 'Which planet is known as the Red Planet?',
            'Options': ['Mars', 'Earth', 'Jupiter', 'Venus'],
            'Correct_Answer': 'Mars',
            'Description': 'Mars is often referred to as the "Red Planet" because of its reddish appearance.'
        },
        {
            'Question': 'Which animal is known for its hump and lives in the desert?',
            'Options': ['Camel', 'Horse', 'Lion', 'Whale'],
            'Correct_Answer': 'Camel',
            'Description': 'Camels have humps that store fat, which they can convert into water and energy.'
        },
        {
            'Question': 'How many days are there in a leap year?',
            'Options': ['365', '366', '364', '367'],
            'Correct_Answer': '366',
            'Description': 'A leap year has an additional day added to February.'
        },
        {
            'Question': 'What color do you get when you mix blue and yellow?',
            'Options': ['Green', 'Orange', 'Purple', 'Brown'],
            'Correct_Answer': 'Green',
            'Description': 'Blue and yellow mixed together produce the color green.'
        },
        {
            'Question': 'Which fruit is known to be the primary ingredient in guacamole?',
            'Options': ['Tomato', 'Mango', 'Avocado', 'Pineapple'],
            'Correct_Answer': 'Avocado',
            'Description': 'Guacamole is an avocado-based dip.'
        },
        {
            'Question': 'What is the capital of France?',
            'Options': ['Berlin', 'Madrid', 'Paris', 'Rome'],
            'Correct_Answer': 'Paris',
            'Description': 'Paris is the capital city of France.'
        },
        {
            'Question': 'Which animal is known as the "King of the Jungle"?',
            'Options': ['Lion', 'Elephant', 'Tiger', 'Wolf'],
            'Correct_Answer': 'Lion',
            'Description': 'Lions are often called the "King of the Jungle".'
        },
        {
            'Question': 'Which bird is known for its beautiful tail feathers and dance?',
            'Options': ['Peacock', 'Penguin', 'Ostrich', 'Eagle'],
            'Correct_Answer': 'Peacock',
            'Description': 'Peacocks are known for their beautiful and colorful tail feathers.'
        },
        {
            'Question': 'What is the primary source of energy for our planet?',
            'Options': ['Moon', 'Stars', 'Sun', 'Clouds'],
            'Correct_Answer': 'Sun',
            'Description': 'The Sun provides the primary energy that powers Earth.'
        },
        {
            'Question': 'Which is the largest mammal?',
            'Options': ['Elephant', 'Whale', 'Giraffe', 'Hippopotamus'],
            'Correct_Answer': 'Whale',
            'Description': 'The blue whale is the largest mammal and the largest animal to have ever lived.'
        }
    ],
    # Level 2
    [
        {
            'Question': 'Which gas is most prevalent in Earth\'s atmosphere?',
            'Options': ['Oxygen', 'Carbon Dioxide', 'Nitrogen', 'Argon'],
            'Correct_Answer': 'Nitrogen',
            'Description': 'Earth\'s atmosphere is roughly 78% nitrogen, making it the most prevalent gas.'
        },
        {
            'Question': 'Which ancient wonder was found in the city of Babylon?',
            'Options': ['Hanging Gardens', 'Pyramid of Giza', 'Lighthouse of Alexandria', 'Statue of Zeus'],
            'Correct_Answer': 'Hanging Gardens',
            'Description': 'The Hanging Gardens are described as an astonishing feat of engineering and are associated with ancient Babylon.'
        },
        {
            'Question': 'Which country is known as the Land of the Rising Sun?',
            'Options': ['China', 'Japan', 'India', 'Russia'],
            'Correct_Answer': 'Japan',
            'Description': 'Japan is often referred to as the Land of the Rising Sun.'
        },
        {
            'Question': 'Who wrote "Romeo and Juliet"?',
            'Options': ['William Shakespeare', 'Jane Austen', 'Mark Twain', 'Charles Dickens'],
            'Correct_Answer': 'William Shakespeare',
            'Description': 'William Shakespeare is the renowned playwright behind "Romeo and Juliet".'
        },
        {
            'Question': 'What is the largest organ in the human body?',
            'Options': ['Heart', 'Liver', 'Lungs', 'Skin'],
            'Correct_Answer': 'Skin',
            'Description': 'The skin is the largest organ in terms of surface area and weight.'
        },
        {
            'Question': 'Which metal is in the liquid state at room temperature?',
            'Options': ['Gold', 'Iron', 'Mercury', 'Silver'],
            'Correct_Answer': 'Mercury',
            'Description': 'Mercury is the only metal that is liquid at room temperature.'
        },
        {
            'Question': 'In Greek mythology, who turned everything he touched into gold?',
            'Options': ['Midas', 'Zeus', 'Hercules', 'Apollo'],
            'Correct_Answer': 'Midas',
            'Description': 'King Midas is known for his ability to turn everything he touched into gold.'
        },
        {
            'Question': 'Which planet has the famous Great Red Spot storm?',
            'Options': ['Mars', 'Jupiter', 'Saturn', 'Venus'],
            'Correct_Answer': 'Jupiter',
            'Description': 'Jupiter\'s Great Red Spot is a massive storm that has raged for at least 350 years.'
        },
        {
            'Question': 'What is the hardest natural substance on Earth?',
            'Options': ['Gold', 'Iron', 'Granite', 'Diamond'],
            'Correct_Answer': 'Diamond',
            'Description': 'Diamond is the hardest known natural material on Earth.'
        },
        {
            'Question': 'Which famous ship sank on its first voyage in 1912?',
            'Options': ['Titanic', 'Queen Mary', 'Mayflower', 'USS Enterprise'],
            'Correct_Answer': 'Titanic',
            'Description': 'The RMS Titanic sank on its maiden voyage in 1912 after hitting an iceberg.'
        }
    ],
    # Level 3
    [
        {
            'question': 'Which chemical element is represented by the symbol "Au"?',
            'options': ['Silver', 'Gold', 'Copper', 'Aluminum'], 
            'answer': 'Gold',
            'description': 'The symbol "Au" comes from the Latin word "aurum", which means gold.'
        },
        {
            'question': 'Which famous battle took place in 1066?',
            'options': ['Battle of Agincourt', 'Battle of Waterloo', 'Battle of Stirling Bridge', 'Battle of Hastings'], 
            'answer': 'Battle of Hastings',
            'description': 'The Battle of Hastings in 1066 was between the Norman-French army and the English army.'
        },
        {
            'question': 'Which planet has a feature known as the "Great Red Spot"?',
            'options': ['Mars', 'Venus', 'Jupiter', 'Saturn'], 
            'answer': 'Jupiter',
            'description': 'Jupiter has a storm known as the Great Red Spot, which has been raging for at least 400 years.'
        },
        {
            'question': 'Which of these elements is a noble gas?',
            'options': ['Nitrogen', 'Oxygen', 'Argon', 'Carbon'], 
            'answer': 'Argon',
            'description': 'Argon is a noble gas, which means it is colorless, odorless, and non-reactive under most conditions.'
        },
        {
            'question': 'Which famous scientist developed the theory of general relativity?',
            'options': ['Niels Bohr', 'Isaac Newton', 'Galileo Galilei', 'Albert Einstein'], 
            'answer': 'Albert Einstein',
            'description': 'Albert Einstein is known for his theory of relativity among other groundbreaking contributions to physics.'
        },
        {
            'question': 'In Greek mythology, who turned everything he touched into gold?',
            'options': ['Zeus', 'Midas', 'Apollo', 'Hercules'], 
            'answer': 'Midas',
            'description': 'King Midas had the unfortunate ability to turn everything he touched into gold.'
        },
        {
            'question': 'Which of these musical instruments is a woodwind?',
            'options': ['Violin', 'Trombone', 'Piano', 'Flute'], 
            'answer': 'Flute',
            'description': 'A flute is a woodwind instrument that produces sound from the flow of air across an opening.'
        },
        {
            'question': 'Which of these countries is landlocked?',
            'options': ['India', 'Australia', 'Brazil', 'Bolivia'], 
            'answer': 'Bolivia',
            'description': 'Bolivia is a landlocked country in South America, surrounded by other countries and without a coastline.'
        },
        {
            'question': 'Which artist painted the "Girl with a Pearl Earring"?',
            'options': ['Leonardo da Vinci', 'Vincent van Gogh', 'Rembrandt', 'Johannes Vermeer'], 
            'answer': 'Johannes Vermeer',
            'description': 'Johannes Vermeer painted the iconic "Girl with a Pearl Earring" in the 17th century.'
        },
        {
            'question': 'Which literary character said, "To be or not to be, that is the question"?',
            'options': ['Macbeth', 'Hamlet', 'Othello', 'Romeo'], 
            'answer': 'Hamlet',
            'description': 'The line "To be or not to be" is one of the most famous soliloquies from Shakespeare\'s play "Hamlet".'
        }
    ],
    # Level 4
    [
        {
            'question': 'Which scientist is known for the principle of buoyancy?',
            'options': ['Galileo Galilei', 'Sir Isaac Newton', 'Archimedes', 'Blaise Pascal'], 
            'answer': 'Archimedes',
            'description': 'Archimedes is credited with the discovery of the principle of buoyancy, often known as Archimedes\' Principle.'
        },
        {
            'question': 'Which country is known as the "Land of the Rising Sun"?',
            'options': ['South Korea', 'China', 'Japan', 'Philippines'], 
            'answer': 'Japan',
            'description': 'Japan is often called the Land of the Rising Sun because it lies to the east of the Asian continent.'
        },
        {
            'question': 'Which of these elements is a liquid at room temperature?',
            'options': ['Gold', 'Mercury', 'Iron', 'Aluminum'], 
            'answer': 'Mercury',
            'description': 'Mercury is a metal that remains liquid at room temperature and is used in thermometers.'
        },
        {
            'question': 'In literature, who wrote the poem "The Raven"?',
            'options': ['Walt Whitman', 'Robert Frost', 'Edgar Allan Poe', 'Emily Dickinson'], 
            'answer': 'Edgar Allan Poe',
            'description': 'Edgar Allan Poe is known for his mysterious and macabre poem "The Raven".'
        },
        {
            'question': 'Which part of the cell is responsible for producing energy?',
            'options': ['Nucleus', 'Endoplasmic Reticulum', 'Golgi Apparatus', 'Mitochondria'], 
            'answer': 'Mitochondria',
            'description': 'Mitochondria, often called the powerhouse of the cell, is responsible for producing energy through cellular respiration.'
        },
        {
            'question': 'Which philosopher wrote the work "Meditations"?',
            'options': ['Plato', 'Nietzsche', 'Marcus Aurelius', 'Descartes'], 
            'answer': 'Marcus Aurelius',
            'description': 'Marcus Aurelius wrote "Meditations", a series of personal writings on Stoic philosophy.'
        },
        {
            'question': 'Which of these is NOT a layer of the Earth’s atmosphere?',
            'options': ['Stratosphere', 'Ionosphere', 'Lithosphere', 'Troposphere'], 
            'answer': 'Lithosphere',
            'description': 'The lithosphere is the rigid outer part of the earth, consisting of the crust and upper mantle.'
        },
        {
            'question': 'Which of these rivers is the longest?',
            'options': ['Amazon', 'Nile', 'Mississippi', 'Yangtze'], 
            'answer': 'Nile',
            'description': 'The Nile is traditionally considered to be the longest river in the world.'
        },
        {
            'question': 'Which of these musical terms refers to a piece’s speed?',
            'options': ['Harmony', 'Timbre', 'Tempo', 'Dynamics'], 
            'answer': 'Tempo',
            'description': 'Tempo is the speed at which a piece of music is played.'
        },
        {
            'question': 'Which of these diseases is caused by a deficiency of Vitamin C?',
            'options': ['Rickets', 'Pellagra', 'Scurvy', 'Beriberi'], 
            'answer': 'Scurvy',
            'description': 'Scurvy is caused by a deficiency of Vitamin C and results in swollen gums, joint pain, and anemia.'
        }
    ],
    # Level 5
    [
        {
            'question': 'Which of these is NOT one of Plato’s dialogues?',
            'options': ['Euthyphro', 'Nicomachean Ethics', 'Meno', 'Phaedrus'], 
            'answer': 'Nicomachean Ethics',
            'description': 'Nicomachean Ethics is a work by Aristotle, not Plato.'
        },
        {
            'question': 'In which of these novels is the character "Atticus Finch" featured?',
            'options': ['The Catcher in the Rye', 'To Kill a Mockingbird', 'Pride and Prejudice', 'Moby Dick'], 
            'answer': 'To Kill a Mockingbird',
            'description': 'Atticus Finch is a central character in Harper Lee\'s "To Kill a Mockingbird".'
        },
        {
            'question': 'Which compound has the chemical formula H2SO4?',
            'options': ['Hydrochloric Acid', 'Acetic Acid', 'Sulfuric Acid', 'Carbonic Acid'], 
            'answer': 'Sulfuric Acid',
            'description': 'H2SO4 is the chemical formula for sulfuric acid.'
        },
        {
            'question': 'Which of these elements is NOT a noble gas?',
            'options': ['Helium', 'Neon', 'Krypton', 'Bromine'], 
            'answer': 'Bromine',
            'description': 'Bromine is a halogen, not a noble gas.'
        },
        {
            'question': 'Who developed the theory of relativity?',
            'options': ['Isaac Newton', 'Niels Bohr', 'Werner Heisenberg', 'Albert Einstein'], 
            'answer': 'Albert Einstein',
            'description': 'Albert Einstein developed the theory of relativity.'
        },
        {
            'question': 'Which planet in our solar system has the most moons?',
            'options': ['Jupiter', 'Saturn', 'Mars', 'Venus'], 
            'answer': 'Jupiter',
            'description': 'Jupiter, the largest planet in our solar system, also has the most moons.'
        },
        {
            'question': 'Which of these authors is NOT associated with the "Lost Generation"?',
            'options': ['Ernest Hemingway', 'F. Scott Fitzgerald', 'Gertrude Stein', 'William Faulkner'], 
            'answer': 'William Faulkner',
            'description': 'While Faulkner is a contemporary of the Lost Generation, he is not typically grouped with them.'
        },
        {
            'question': 'Which of these instruments is NOT a woodwind?',
            'options': ['Flute', 'Clarinet', 'Tuba', 'Oboe'], 
            'answer': 'Tuba',
            'description': 'The tuba is a brass instrument, not a woodwind.'
        },
        {
            'question': 'Who painted the artwork known as "The Persistence of Memory"?',
            'options': ['Pablo Picasso', 'Salvador Dalí', 'Vincent van Gogh', 'Jackson Pollock'], 
            'answer': 'Salvador Dalí',
            'description': 'Salvador Dalí is known for "The Persistence of Memory", which features melting clocks.'
        },
        {
            'question': 'In what process do plants convert carbon dioxide into glucose?',
            'options': ['Digestion', 'Cellular Respiration', 'Fermentation', 'Photosynthesis'], 
            'answer': 'Photosynthesis',
            'description': 'During photosynthesis, plants convert carbon dioxide and sunlight into glucose and oxygen.'
        }
    ],
    # Level 6
    [
        {
            'question': 'Which philosopher wrote the work "Critique of Pure Reason"?',
            'options': ['Immanuel Kant', 'Friedrich Nietzsche', 'John Locke', 'Thomas Hobbes'], 
            'answer': 'Immanuel Kant',
            'description': 'Immanuel Kant wrote the "Critique of Pure Reason," which discusses epistemology and metaphysics.'
        },
        {
            'question': 'What is the primary function of the mitochondria in cells?',
            'options': ['Protein Synthesis', 'Photosynthesis', 'Cell Division', 'Energy Production'], 
            'answer': 'Energy Production',
            'description': 'Mitochondria are often referred to as the "powerhouses" of the cell because they produce energy.'
        },
        {
            'question': 'Which playwright wrote "The Cherry Orchard" and "Three Sisters"?',
            'options': ['Tennessee Williams', 'Eugene O\'Neill', 'Anton Chekhov', 'George Bernard Shaw'], 
            'answer': 'Anton Chekhov',
            'description': 'Anton Chekhov, a Russian playwright, wrote both "The Cherry Orchard" and "Three Sisters".'
        },
        {
            'question': 'Which city was historically known as Byzantium and later became the capital of the Ottoman Empire?',
            'options': ['Athens', 'Rome', 'Cairo', 'Istanbul'], 
            'answer': 'Istanbul',
            'description': 'Istanbul, previously known as Byzantium and later as Constantinople, was the capital of both the Byzantine and Ottoman Empires.'
        },
        {
            'question': 'What is the term for an organism that can live without oxygen?',
            'options': ['Herbivore', 'Anaerobe', 'Carnivore', 'Autotroph'], 
            'answer': 'Anaerobe',
            'description': 'Anaerobes are organisms that do not require oxygen for growth.'
        },
        {
            'question': 'Which chemical element has the atomic number 92?',
            'options': ['Plutonium', 'Thorium', 'Radium', 'Uranium'], 
            'answer': 'Uranium',
            'description': 'Uranium has the atomic number 92.'
        },
        {
            'question': 'Which of the following is NOT a book in the Old Testament of the Bible?',
            'options': ['Genesis', 'Leviticus', 'Hebrews', 'Exodus'], 
            'answer': 'Hebrews',
            'description': 'Hebrews is a book in the New Testament, not the Old Testament.'
        },
        {
            'question': 'Which river flows through the Grand Canyon?',
            'options': ['Mississippi River', 'Colorado River', 'Yellow River', 'Amazon River'], 
            'answer': 'Colorado River',
            'description': 'The Grand Canyon was carved by the Colorado River over millions of years.'
        },
        {
            'question': 'Who was the first Roman Emperor?',
            'options': ['Julius Caesar', 'Nero', 'Augustus', 'Caligula'], 
            'answer': 'Augustus',
            'description': 'Augustus, previously known as Octavian, became the first Roman Emperor.'
        },
        {
            'question': 'In what country is the historic region of Transylvania located?',
            'options': ['Hungary', 'Bulgaria', 'Poland', 'Romania'], 
            'answer': 'Romania',
            'description': 'Transylvania is a historic region located in central Romania.'
        }
    ],
    # Level 7
    [
        {
            'question': 'Which composer created the "Moonlight Sonata"?',
            'options': ['Johann Sebastian Bach', 'Wolfgang Amadeus Mozart', 'Ludwig van Beethoven', 'Franz Schubert'], 
            'answer': 'Ludwig van Beethoven',
            'description': 'The "Moonlight Sonata" is one of Beethoven\'s most recognized and played compositions.'
        },
        {
            'question': 'Which of these is NOT a moon of Jupiter?',
            'options': ['Io', 'Titan', 'Europa', 'Callisto'], 
            'answer': 'Titan',
            'description': 'Titan is the largest moon of Saturn, not Jupiter.'
        },
        {
            'question': 'Which scientist is known for his uncertainty principle in quantum mechanics?',
            'options': ['Isaac Newton', 'Albert Einstein', 'Niels Bohr', 'Werner Heisenberg'], 
            'answer': 'Werner Heisenberg',
            'description': 'Werner Heisenberg introduced the uncertainty principle in the realm of quantum mechanics.'
        },
        {
            'question': 'What is the capital of New Zealand?',
            'options': ['Sydney', 'Auckland', 'Wellington', 'Christchurch'], 
            'answer': 'Wellington',
            'description': 'Wellington is the capital city of New Zealand.'
        },
        {
            'question': 'In literature, who wrote "Brave New World"?',
            'options': ['George Orwell', 'Aldous Huxley', 'Ray Bradbury', 'Kurt Vonnegut'], 
            'answer': 'Aldous Huxley',
            'description': 'Aldous Huxley wrote the dystopian novel "Brave New World".'
        },
        {
            'question': 'Which element is liquid at room temperature and is used in thermometers?',
            'options': ['Lead', 'Mercury', 'Aluminum', 'Copper'], 
            'answer': 'Mercury',
            'description': 'Mercury is a metal that is liquid at room temperature and is used in thermometers.'
        },
        {
            'question': 'Who is credited with proposing the theory of evolution by natural selection?',
            'options': ['Charles Darwin', 'Gregor Mendel', 'Louis Pasteur', 'James Watson'], 
            'answer': 'Charles Darwin',
            'description': 'Charles Darwin is known for proposing the theory of evolution by natural selection.'
        },
        {
            'question': 'Which ancient civilization built the city of Machu Picchu?',
            'options': ['The Aztecs', 'The Mayans', 'The Incas', 'The Olmecs'], 
            'answer': 'The Incas',
            'description': 'Machu Picchu is an ancient Incan city located in the Andes Mountains.'
        },
        {
            'question': 'In which century did the Renaissance primarily take place?',
            'options': ['12th Century', '14th Century', '16th Century', '18th Century'], 
            'answer': '14th Century',
            'description': 'The Renaissance primarily began in the 14th century and lasted into the 17th century.'
        },
        {
            'question': 'Which artist is famous for the sculpture "David" and the Sistine Chapel ceiling?',
            'options': ['Michelangelo', 'Raphael', 'Leonardo da Vinci', 'Donatello'], 
            'answer': 'Michelangelo',
            'description': 'Michelangelo is renowned for creating the sculpture "David" and painting the Sistine Chapel ceiling.'
        }
    ],
    # Level 8
    [
        {
            'question': 'Which philosopher wrote the work "Meditations"?',
            'options': ['Plato', 'Aristotle', 'Socrates', 'Marcus Aurelius'], 
            'answer': 'Marcus Aurelius',
            'description': '"Meditations" is a series of personal writings by Marcus Aurelius on Stoic philosophy.'
        },
        {
            'question': 'What is the term for animals that only eat plants?',
            'options': ['Carnivore', 'Omnivore', 'Herbivore', 'Detritivore'], 
            'answer': 'Herbivore',
            'description': 'Herbivores are animals that consume only plants.'
        },
        {
            'question': 'Which physicist is primarily known for his theory of relativity?',
            'options': ['Isaac Newton', 'Niels Bohr', 'Albert Einstein', 'James Clerk Maxwell'], 
            'answer': 'Albert Einstein',
            'description': 'Albert Einstein proposed the theory of relativity, one of the two pillars of modern physics.'
        },
        {
            'question': 'Which of these elements is radioactive?',
            'options': ['Gold', 'Silver', 'Uranium', 'Iron'], 
            'answer': 'Uranium',
            'description': 'Uranium is a radioactive element used as fuel in nuclear reactors.'
        },
        {
            'question': 'What language was primarily spoken in the ancient Roman Empire?',
            'options': ['Greek', 'Latin', 'Aramaic', 'Egyptian'], 
            'answer': 'Latin',
            'description': 'Latin was the language of the Roman Republic and the Roman Empire.'
        },
        {
            'question': 'Which planet in our solar system has a day that lasts longer than its year?',
            'options': ['Mars', 'Venus', 'Jupiter', 'Saturn'], 
            'answer': 'Venus',
            'description': 'A day on Venus, from one sunrise to the next, lasts longer than a Venusian year.'
        },
        {
            'question': 'What does the medical term "cardio" refer to?',
            'options': ['Brain', 'Liver', 'Heart', 'Lung'], 
            'answer': 'Heart',
            'description': 'The term "cardio" relates to the heart.'
        },
        {
            'question': 'Which author wrote the dystopian novel "Fahrenheit 451"?',
            'options': ['Kurt Vonnegut', 'Ray Bradbury', 'Aldous Huxley', 'Orwell'], 
            'answer': 'Ray Bradbury',
            'description': 'Ray Bradbury wrote "Fahrenheit 451", a dystopian novel about a future American society where books are outlawed.'
        },
        {
            'question': 'Which of the following is NOT a noble gas?',
            'options': ['Argon', 'Neon', 'Chlorine', 'Helium'], 
            'answer': 'Chlorine',
            'description': 'Chlorine is a halogen, not a noble gas.'
        },
        {
            'question': 'Who is known as the "Father of the Computer"?',
            'options': ['Steve Jobs', 'Bill Gates', 'Alan Turing', 'Charles Babbage'], 
            'answer': 'Charles Babbage',
            'description': 'Charles Babbage is credited with designing the first mechanical computer, known as the Analytical Engine.'
        }
    ],
    # Level 9
    [
        {
            'question': 'What is the main component of natural gas?',
            'options': ['Carbon Dioxide', 'Oxygen', 'Methane', 'Helium'], 
            'answer': 'Methane',
            'description': 'Natural gas is primarily composed of methane, along with small amounts of other gases.'
        },
        {
            'question': 'Who is known as the "Maid of Orléans"?',
            'options': ['Cleopatra', 'Joan of Arc', 'Marie Curie', 'Mary, Queen of Scots'], 
            'answer': 'Joan of Arc',
            'description': 'Joan of Arc is also known as the "Maid of Orléans" and is a national heroine of France.'
        },
        {
            'question': 'Which chemical compound is known as table salt?',
            'options': ['NaOH', 'H2O', 'CO2', 'NaCl'], 
            'answer': 'NaCl',
            'description': 'NaCl, or sodium chloride, is commonly known as table salt.'
        },
        {
            'question': 'Which Greek philosopher taught Alexander the Great?',
            'options': ['Plato', 'Aristotle', 'Socrates', 'Pythagoras'], 
            'answer': 'Aristotle',
            'description': 'Aristotle was a tutor to Alexander the Great.'
        },
        {
            'question': 'Which body part continues to grow throughout a person’s lifetime?',
            'options': ['Ears', 'Legs', 'Hands', 'Heart'], 
            'answer': 'Ears',
            'description': 'Ears (and also the nose) continue to grow throughout a person’s life, due to gravity and collagen production.'
        },
        {
            'question': 'Which writer is best known for "The Metamorphosis", a short story about a man who turns into an insect?',
            'options': ['Franz Kafka', 'Fyodor Dostoevsky', 'James Joyce', 'Ernest Hemingway'], 
            'answer': 'Franz Kafka',
            'description': 'Franz Kafka wrote "The Metamorphosis", a novella about a man named Gregor Samsa who wakes up one day to find himself transformed into a giant insect.'
        },
        {
            'question': 'Which architectural style is characterized by pointed arches, ribbed vaults, and flying buttresses?',
            'options': ['Baroque', 'Renaissance', 'Romanesque', 'Gothic'], 
            'answer': 'Gothic',
            'description': 'Gothic architecture is characterized by elements like pointed arches, ribbed vaults, and flying buttresses.'
        },
        {
            'question': 'Which particle is exchanged in the electrolyte of a battery?',
            'options': ['Electron', 'Proton', 'Neutron', 'Photon'], 
            'answer': 'Electron',
            'description': 'In a battery, electrons flow from the anode to the cathode, producing an electric current.'
        },
        {
            'question': 'What is the primary function of red blood cells?',
            'options': ['Fight infection', 'Clot blood', 'Transport oxygen', 'Produce hormones'], 
            'answer': 'Transport oxygen',
            'description': 'Red blood cells, or erythrocytes, primarily transport oxygen from the lungs to the body’s cells.'
        },
        {
            'question': 'Which element is known as the "King of Chemicals" due to its importance in chemical industry?',
            'options': ['Oxygen', 'Carbon', 'Hydrogen', 'Sulfur'], 
            'answer': 'Sulfur',
            'description': 'Sulfuric acid is often referred to as the "King of Chemicals" because of its pivotal role in manufacturing and industrial processes.'
        }
    ],
    # Level 10
    [
        {
            'question': 'Which physicist is best known for the theory of relativity?',
            'options': ['Isaac Newton', 'Niels Bohr', 'Albert Einstein', 'Max Planck'], 
            'answer': 'Albert Einstein',
            'description': 'Albert Einstein proposed the theory of relativity and is one of the most influential physicists of the 20th century.'
        },
        {
            'question': 'Which musical instrument is known for having 88 keys?',
            'options': ['Guitar', 'Violin', 'Piano', 'Flute'], 
            'answer': 'Piano',
            'description': 'A standard piano has 88 keys, comprising of 52 white and 36 black keys.'
        },
        {
            'question': 'Which element has the atomic number 79?',
            'options': ['Iron', 'Gold', 'Silver', 'Copper'], 
            'answer': 'Gold',
            'description': 'Gold has the atomic number 79 on the periodic table.'
        },
        {
            'question': 'Which author wrote the dystopian novel "Brave New World"?',
            'options': ['George Orwell', 'John Steinbeck', 'Aldous Huxley', 'Ray Bradbury'], 
            'answer': 'Aldous Huxley',
            'description': 'Aldous Huxley wrote "Brave New World", a novel that depicts a futuristic society driven by technological advancements.'
        },
        {
            'question': 'In mathematics, what does the Greek letter π (pi) represent?',
            'options': ['Golden ratio', 'Circle’s diameter', 'Base of natural logarithm', 'Ratio of a circle’s circumference to its diameter'], 
            'answer': 'Ratio of a circle’s circumference to its diameter',
            'description': 'The Greek letter π (pi) represents the ratio of a circle’s circumference to its diameter, approximately 3.14159.'
        },
        {
            'question': 'Which philosopher is credited with the allegory of the cave?',
            'options': ['Aristotle', 'Plato', 'Socrates', 'Descartes'], 
            'answer': 'Plato',
            'description': 'Plato’s allegory of the cave is found in his work "The Republic" and describes people trapped in a cave and only seeing shadows of the outside world.'
        },
        {
            'question': 'Which compound is known as the "universal solvent"?',
            'options': ['Acetone', 'Water', 'Alcohol', 'Mercury'], 
            'answer': 'Water',
            'description': 'Water is often referred to as the "universal solvent" because it can dissolve a wide variety of substances.'
        },
        {
            'question': 'Which planet has the most moons in our solar system?',
            'options': ['Mars', 'Jupiter', 'Saturn', 'Uranus'], 
            'answer': 'Jupiter',
            'description': 'As of my last update, Jupiter holds the record for the most moons, though it is a subject of ongoing discovery and may change.'
        },
        {
            'question': 'What does DNA stand for?',
            'options': ['Dioxyribo Nucleic Acid', 'Deoxyribonucleic Acid', 'Dioxyribonucleotide Acid', 'Deoxynucleotide Acid'], 
            'answer': 'Deoxyribonucleic Acid',
            'description': 'DNA stands for Deoxyribonucleic Acid and contains the genetic instructions for the development and function of living things.'
        },
        {
            'question': 'Which Renaissance artist painted the "Vitruvian Man"?',
            'options': ['Raphael', 'Leonardo da Vinci', 'Michelangelo', 'Donatello'], 
            'answer': 'Leonardo da Vinci',
            'description': 'Leonardo da Vinci created the "Vitruvian Man", a drawing that depicts the proportions of the human body.'
        }
    ],
    # Level 11
    [
        {
            'question': 'Which psychological principle suggests that tasks of moderate difficulty elicit the highest levels of arousal and performance?',
            'options': ['Maslow’s hierarchy', 'Freud’s psychoanalysis', 'Skinner’s operant conditioning', 'Yerkes-Dodson law'], 
            'answer': 'Yerkes-Dodson law',
            'description': 'The Yerkes-Dodson law posits an empirical relationship between arousal and performance.'
        },
        {
            'question': 'What is the primary process for cellular energy production in eukaryotes?',
            'options': ['Glycolysis', 'Fermentation', 'Osmosis', 'Oxidative phosphorylation'], 
            'answer': 'Oxidative phosphorylation',
            'description': 'Oxidative phosphorylation takes place in the mitochondria and produces ATP from ADP and inorganic phosphate.'
        },
        {
            'question': 'Which literary work explores the concept of an overpopulated world where people are conditioned for specific roles and personal identity is a foreign concept?',
            'options': ['1984', 'Fahrenheit 451', 'Brave New World', 'The Time Machine'], 
            'answer': 'Brave New World',
            'description': 'Aldous Huxley’s "Brave New World" delves into a future of extreme societal control and lack of individual autonomy.'
        },
        {
            'question': 'What is the study of fungi called?',
            'options': ['Herpetology', 'Mycology', 'Botany', 'Entomology'], 
            'answer': 'Mycology',
            'description': 'Mycology is the branch of biology concerned with the study of fungi, including their genetic and biochemical properties.'
        },
        {
            'question': 'Which scientist is known for the uncertainty principle in quantum mechanics?',
            'options': ['Niels Bohr', 'Albert Einstein', 'Isaac Newton', 'Werner Heisenberg'], 
            'answer': 'Werner Heisenberg',
            'description': 'Werner Heisenberg proposed the uncertainty principle, fundamental to quantum mechanics.'
        },
        {
            'question': 'In which part of the cell does translation, the process of protein synthesis, primarily occur?',
            'options': ['Nucleus', 'Mitochondria', 'Ribosomes', 'Golgi apparatus'], 
            'answer': 'Ribosomes',
            'description': 'Ribosomes read RNA sequences and assemble corresponding amino acids to produce proteins, in a process called translation.'
        },
        {
            'question': 'Which mathematician and logician is known for the incompleteness theorems?',
            'options': ['Bertrand Russell', 'Isaac Newton', 'Leonhard Euler', 'Kurt Gödel'], 
            'answer': 'Kurt Gödel',
            'description': 'Kurt Gödel is renowned for his incompleteness theorems, which have profound implications for the foundations of mathematics.'
        },
        {
            'question': 'Which of the following is NOT one of the four fundamental forces of nature?',
            'options': ['Electromagnetic force', 'Gravitational force', 'Nuclear force', 'Centripetal force'], 
            'answer': 'Centripetal force',
            'description': 'Centripetal force is not one of the fundamental forces. The four fundamental forces are gravitational, electromagnetic, strong nuclear, and weak nuclear forces.'
        },
        {
            'question': 'What is the phenomenon where light or other electromagnetic radiation from an object is increased in wavelength, or shifted towards the red end of the spectrum?',
            'options': ['Photoelectric effect', 'Diffraction', 'Redshift', 'Refraction'], 
            'answer': 'Redshift',
            'description': 'Redshift occurs when the source of light moves away from the observer, causing the light to appear redder than it originally was.'
        },
        {
            'question': 'Which element is known as the “King of Chemicals” due to its extensive usage and diverse application in the chemical industry?',
            'options': ['Hydrogen', 'Oxygen', 'Carbon', 'Sulfur'], 
            'answer': 'Sulfur',
            'description': 'Sulfur, due to its diverse applications, is often referred to as the "King of Chemicals".'
        }
    ],
    # Level 12
    [
        {
            'question': 'Who proposed the theory of conditioned reflexes based on his experiments with dogs?',
            'options': ['John B. Watson', 'B.F. Skinner', 'Carl Rogers', 'Ivan Pavlov'], 
            'answer': 'Ivan Pavlov',
            'description': 'Ivan Pavlov is known for his pioneering work in classical conditioning using dogs.'
        },
        {
            'question': 'Which of the following is the hardest naturally occurring substance on Earth?',
            'options': ['Ruby', 'Graphite', 'Quartz', 'Diamond'], 
            'answer': 'Diamond',
            'description': 'Diamond, a form of carbon, is the hardest naturally occurring substance on Earth.'
        },
        {
            'question': 'Which mathematical conundrum involves the task of connecting nine dots with four straight lines without lifting the pencil from the paper?',
            'options': ['Königsberg bridge problem', 'Four color theorem', 'Monty Hall problem', 'Nine dots puzzle'], 
            'answer': 'Nine dots puzzle',
            'description': 'The Nine dots puzzle is an exercise in lateral thinking and goes beyond the perceived boundaries.'
        },
        {
            'question': 'Which physicist is best known for his theory of electromagnetism?',
            'options': ['Niels Bohr', 'Isaac Newton', 'James Clerk Maxwell', 'Michael Faraday'], 
            'answer': 'James Clerk Maxwell',
            'description': 'James Clerk Maxwell formulated the classical theory of electromagnetic radiation, which is fundamental in physics.'
        },
        {
            'question': 'Which philosopher posited the allegory of the cave, highlighting the difference between the world of appearances and the real world of ideas?',
            'options': ['Socrates', 'Aristotle', 'Plato', 'Immanuel Kant'], 
            'answer': 'Plato',
            'description': 'Plato’s allegory of the cave describes prisoners who have been chained in a cave their entire lives, seeing only shadows, which they believe to be reality.'
        },
        {
            'question': 'What is the primary molecule that stores and transfers energy in cells?',
            'options': ['DNA', 'Hemoglobin', 'Insulin', 'ATP'], 
            'answer': 'ATP',
            'description': 'Adenosine Triphosphate (ATP) is often referred to as the energy currency of the cell.'
        },
        {
            'question': 'Which mathematical constant represents the ratio of the circumference of a circle to its diameter?',
            'options': ['e', 'π', 'Φ', 'i'], 
            'answer': 'π',
            'description': 'π (Pi) is the constant that represents the ratio of a circle’s circumference to its diameter.'
        },
        {
            'question': 'Which neurotransmitter is primarily involved in the reward and pleasure centers of the brain and is often linked with addiction?',
            'options': ['Serotonin', 'Acetylcholine', 'Dopamine', 'Norepinephrine'], 
            'answer': 'Dopamine',
            'description': 'Dopamine plays a major role in the brain system that is responsible for reward-driven learning and pleasure sensations.'
        },
        {
            'question': 'Which astronomical phenomenon occurs when the moon comes between the Earth and the sun, thereby covering the sun entirely or partially?',
            'options': ['Solar flare', 'Solar eclipse', 'Lunar eclipse', 'Blue moon'], 
            'answer': 'Solar eclipse',
            'description': 'A solar eclipse occurs when the moon passes between the sun and the Earth, and the moon fully or partially blocks the sun from view.'
        },
        {
            'question': 'Which chemical element is named after the sun due to its presence in solar spectra?',
            'options': ['Helium', 'Neon', 'Plutonium', 'Mercury'], 
            'answer': 'Helium',
            'description': 'Helium, derived from the Greek word "helios" meaning sun, was named because it was first detected in solar spectra.'
        }
    ],
    # Level 13
    [
        {
            'question': 'Which philosopher formulated the categorical imperative as a foundational element of his philosophy?',
            'options': ['Friedrich Nietzsche', 'David Hume', 'Immanuel Kant', 'John Locke'], 
            'answer': 'Immanuel Kant',
            'description': 'Immanuel Kant\'s categorical imperative is a central philosophical concept in his deontological moral philosophy.'
        },
        {
            'question': 'What quantum mechanical phenomenon allows particles to exist in multiple states simultaneously until observed?',
            'options': ['Quantum entanglement', 'Quantum superposition', 'Quantum tunneling', 'Quantum teleportation'], 
            'answer': 'Quantum superposition',
            'description': 'Quantum superposition implies that a particle can exist in multiple states at once until measured or observed.'
        },
        {
            'question': 'Which ancient civilization had a script known as cuneiform?',
            'options': ['Ancient Egyptian', 'Ancient Greek', 'Sumerian', 'Mayan'], 
            'answer': 'Sumerian',
            'description': 'Cuneiform script is one of the earliest systems of writing, developed by the Sumerians.'
        },
        {
            'question': 'Which genetic phenomenon refers to the phenomenon where genes located on one chromosome may be inherited together?',
            'options': ['Dominance', 'Recombination', 'Gene expression', 'Linkage'], 
            'answer': 'Linkage',
            'description': 'Gene linkage refers to the inheritance of genes that are closely located on the same chromosome, and thus tend to be inherited together.'
        },
        {
            'question': 'Which mathematician is known for the uncertainty principle in quantum mechanics?',
            'options': ['Niels Bohr', 'Albert Einstein', 'Max Planck', 'Werner Heisenberg'], 
            'answer': 'Werner Heisenberg',
            'description': 'Werner Heisenberg formulated the uncertainty principle, which is fundamental in quantum mechanics.'
        },
        {
            'question': 'Which Greek mathematician is known for shouting "Eureka!" after making a significant discovery in the field of buoyancy?',
            'options': ['Pythagoras', 'Archimedes', 'Euclid', 'Aristotle'], 
            'answer': 'Archimedes',
            'description': 'Archimedes reportedly shouted "Eureka!" (meaning "I have found it!") when he made a discovery related to buoyancy while taking a bath.'
        },
        {
            'question': 'Which novel by Aldous Huxley presents a dystopian future driven by technological advancements?',
            'options': ['1984', 'The War of the Worlds', 'Brave New World', 'Atlas Shrugged'], 
            'answer': 'Brave New World',
            'description': 'Aldous Huxley\'s "Brave New World" depicts a futuristic society where people are controlled by technological advancements and state-imposed happiness.'
        },
        {
            'question': 'What is the term for organisms that can live and thrive in extremely high-temperature environments?',
            'options': ['Halophiles', 'Cryophiles', 'Thermophiles', 'Xerophiles'], 
            'answer': 'Thermophiles',
            'description': 'Thermophiles are microorganisms that thrive at relatively high temperatures, between 41 and 122°C.'
        },
        {
            'question': 'What phenomenon, which contributes to global warming, involves the trapping of the sun\'s warmth in a planet\'s lower atmosphere due to the greater transparency of the atmosphere to visible radiation from the sun than to infrared radiation emitted from the planet\'s surface?',
            'options': ['Greenhouse effect', 'Ozone depletion', 'Nuclear winter', 'Solar irradiance'], 
            'answer': 'Greenhouse effect',
            'description': 'The greenhouse effect is a natural process that warms the Earth’s surface, but human activities have significantly enhanced this effect, leading to more global warming.'
        },
        {
            'question': 'Which mathematician and logician is known for the incompleteness theorems, which have implications for the foundations of mathematics?',
            'options': ['Alfred North Whitehead', 'Bertrand Russell', 'Kurt Gödel', 'Georg Cantor'], 
            'answer': 'Kurt Gödel',
            'description': 'Kurt Gödel\'s incompleteness theorems are two of the most famous results in the history of mathematical logic.'
        }
    ],
    # Level 14
    [
        {
            'question': 'What branch of mathematics deals with properties and relationships of shapes and the nature of space?',
            'options': ['Algebra', 'Calculus', 'Geometry', 'Statistics'], 
            'answer': 'Geometry',
            'description': 'Geometry is concerned with various dimensions of objects and space and is an ancient branch of mathematics.'
        },
        {
            'question': 'Which physicist is known for his theory of electromagnetism?',
            'options': ['Isaac Newton', 'James Clerk Maxwell', 'Albert Einstein', 'Niels Bohr'], 
            'answer': 'James Clerk Maxwell',
            'description': 'James Clerk Maxwell formulated the classical theory of electromagnetic radiation.'
        },
        {
            'question': 'In literature, who wrote the six-volume series "In Search of Lost Time"?',
            'options': ['Marcel Proust', 'Leo Tolstoy', 'F. Scott Fitzgerald', 'Franz Kafka'], 
            'answer': 'Marcel Proust',
            'description': 'Marcel Proust\'s "In Search of Lost Time" is one of the longest novels and is recognized for its theme of involuntary memory.'
        },
        {
            'question': 'Which theory in physics attempts to reconcile general relativity with quantum mechanics?',
            'options': ['Chaos theory', 'Thermodynamics', 'String theory', 'Electrodynamics'], 
            'answer': 'String theory',
            'description': 'String theory is a theoretical framework in which the point-like particles of particle physics are replaced by one-dimensional objects known as strings.'
        },
        {
            'question': 'Which philosopher is known for the statement "Cogito, ergo sum" (I think, therefore I am)?',
            'options': ['Socrates', 'John Locke', 'René Descartes', 'Friedrich Nietzsche'], 
            'answer': 'René Descartes',
            'description': 'René Descartes formulated this fundamental element of Western philosophy.'
        },
        {
            'question': 'Which biochemist was awarded the Nobel Prize for the discovery of the structure of DNA?',
            'options': ['Marie Curie', 'Linus Pauling', 'Albert Einstein', 'James Watson and Francis Crick'], 
            'answer': 'James Watson and Francis Crick',
            'description': 'James Watson and Francis Crick discovered the double helix structure of DNA.'
        },
        {
            'question': 'Which branch of philosophy deals with the study of values, including ethics, aesthetics, and the nature of the good?',
            'options': ['Metaphysics', 'Epistemology', 'Logic', 'Axiology'], 
            'answer': 'Axiology',
            'description': 'Axiology is the philosophical study of value, including both aesthetic value and ethical value.'
        },
        {
            'question': 'Which ancient civilization developed the concept of zero?',
            'options': ['Ancient Greeks', 'Ancient Egyptians', 'Ancient Chinese', 'Ancient Indians'], 
            'answer': 'Ancient Indians',
            'description': 'The concept of zero as a number was developed in Ancient India.'
        },
        {
            'question': 'What neurological disorder is characterized by recurrent seizures?',
            'options': ['Alzheimer\'s disease', 'Parkinson\'s disease', 'Epilepsy', 'Multiple sclerosis'], 
            'answer': 'Epilepsy',
            'description': 'Epilepsy is a chronic disorder that causes unprovoked, recurrent seizures.'
        },
        {
            'question': 'Which element, used in making computer chips, is the most abundant element in the Earth\'s crust?',
            'options': ['Carbon', 'Iron', 'Oxygen', 'Silicon'], 
            'answer': 'Silicon',
            'description': 'Silicon is used extensively in computer chips and is the second most abundant element in the Earth\'s crust.'
        }
    ],
    # Level 15
    [
        {
            'question': 'What is the most common type of star in the Milky Way?',
            'options': ['Red giant', 'White dwarf', 'Red dwarf', 'Supergiant'], 
            'answer': 'Red dwarf',
            'description': 'Red dwarfs are the most numerous type of star in the Milky Way and likely in the universe.'
        },
        {
            'question': 'Who is known for the Uncertainty Principle in quantum mechanics?',
            'options': ['Albert Einstein', 'Richard Feynman', 'Max Planck', 'Werner Heisenberg'], 
            'answer': 'Werner Heisenberg',
            'description': 'Werner Heisenberg is best known for the Uncertainty Principle in the domain of quantum mechanics.'
        },
        {
            'question': 'Which ancient manuscript consists of complex calculations of the movement of celestial bodies?',
            'options': ['Book of the Dead', 'The Rosetta Stone', 'The Dead Sea Scrolls', 'The Vedas'], 
            'answer': 'The Vedas',
            'description': 'The Vedas, ancient Hindu scriptures, contain various complex astronomical calculations.'
        },
        {
            'question': 'Which philosopher presented the allegory of the cave?',
            'options': ['Aristotle', 'Plato', 'Socrates', 'Confucius'], 
            'answer': 'Plato',
            'description': 'Plato presented the allegory of the cave in his work "The Republic".'
        },
        {
            'question': 'Which biological phenomenon explains the diversification of life over generations through hereditary transmission of variations in populations?',
            'options': ['Photosynthesis', 'Respiration', 'Digestion', 'Evolution'], 
            'answer': 'Evolution',
            'description': 'Evolution is the change in characteristics of a species over several generations based on the process of natural selection.'
        },
        {
            'question': 'What concept in physics refers to the change of velocity of an object with respect to time?',
            'options': ['Momentum', 'Acceleration', 'Force', 'Gravity'], 
            'answer': 'Acceleration',
            'description': 'Acceleration is a vector quantity that represents the rate of change of velocity of an object.'
        },
        {
            'question': 'Who formulated the laws of motion and universal gravitation?',
            'options': ['Galileo Galilei', 'Isaac Newton', 'Albert Einstein', 'Niels Bohr'], 
            'answer': 'Isaac Newton',
            'description': 'Sir Isaac Newton formulated the three laws of motion and the law of universal gravitation.'
        },
        {
            'question': 'Which of these elements is a noble gas?',
            'options': ['Chlorine', 'Oxygen', 'Argon', 'Bromine'], 
            'answer': 'Argon',
            'description': 'Argon is a noble gas, which means it doesn\'t typically engage in chemical reactions because of its filled valence electron shell.'
        },
        {
            'question': 'Which molecule carries the genetic information of an organism?',
            'options': ['Protein', 'Amino acid', 'DNA', 'Lipid'], 
            'answer': 'DNA',
            'description': 'DNA (Deoxyribonucleic acid) carries the genetic instructions for the development and functioning of all known living organisms.'
        },
        {
            'question': 'Which mathematical constant is approximately equal to 3.14159?',
            'options': ['Golden ratio', 'Euler\'s number', 'Pi', 'Avogadro\'s number'], 
            'answer': 'Pi',
            'description': 'Pi (π) is a mathematical constant representing the ratio of a circle\'s circumference to its diameter. It is approximately 3.14159.'
        }
    ],
    # Level 16
    [
        {
            'question': 'Which phenomenon explains the particle-wave duality observed at the quantum level?',
            'options': ['Theory of relativity', 'Quantum entanglement', 'Quantum superposition', 'Newtonian mechanics'], 
            'answer': 'Quantum superposition',
            'description': 'Quantum superposition is a fundamental principle of quantum mechanics that states a quantum system can exist in multiple states or places simultaneously.'
        },
        {
            'question': 'Who is known for the development of the theory of general relativity?',
            'options': ['Isaac Newton', 'Albert Einstein', 'James Clerk Maxwell', 'Michael Faraday'], 
            'answer': 'Albert Einstein',
            'description': 'Albert Einstein formulated the theory of general relativity, which describes the gravitational force as a curvature of spacetime.'
        },
        {
            'question': 'Which mathematical problem, if solved, would revolutionize the field of computer science due to its implications on encryption?',
            'options': ['Fermat\'s Last Theorem', 'Riemann Hypothesis', 'Four Color Theorem', 'P=NP problem'], 
            'answer': 'P=NP problem',
            'description': 'The P=NP problem is a major unsolved question in computer science. Solving it could have profound implications on encryption and many algorithms.'
        },
        {
            'question': 'Which particle is postulated as the reason for imparting mass to other particles but was elusive until recent times?',
            'options': ['Photon', 'Gluon', 'Neutrino', 'Higgs Boson'], 
            'answer': 'Higgs Boson',
            'description': 'The Higgs Boson, often referred to as the "God Particle", is postulated to give other particles their mass and was confirmed at CERN in 2012.'
        },
        {
            'question': 'In string theory, how many dimensions are hypothesized to exist?',
            'options': ['3', '4', '10', '26'], 
            'answer': '10',
            'description': 'String theory, in its most popular variants, proposes that the universe is made up of 10 dimensions - 3 spatial, 1 time, and 6 compactified dimensions.'
        },
        {
            'question': 'Which element was named after the planet Uranus?',
            'options': ['Uranium', 'Neptunium', 'Plutonium', 'Earthium'], 
            'answer': 'Uranium',
            'description': 'Uranium was named after the planet Uranus, following a tradition of naming newly discovered elements after recently discovered planets.'
        },
        {
            'question': 'Which mathematical constant represents the base of the natural logarithm?',
            'options': ['Pi (π)', 'Golden ratio (φ)', 'Euler\'s number (e)', 'Imaginary unit (i)'], 
            'answer': 'Euler\'s number (e)',
            'description': 'Euler\'s number, denoted as (e), represents the base of the natural logarithm and is approximately 2.71828.'
        },
        {
            'question': 'In the field of AI, which test proposes that a machine can be considered "intelligent" if its responses are indistinguishable from a human?',
            'options': ['Captcha Test', 'Alpha Test', 'Turing Test', 'Rorschach Test'], 
            'answer': 'Turing Test',
            'description': 'The Turing Test, proposed by Alan Turing, suggests that a machine can be deemed intelligent if its responses can\'t be differentiated from a human\'s responses.'
        },
        {
            'question': 'Which astronomer proposed the heliocentric model of the Solar System?',
            'options': ['Galileo Galilei', 'Ptolemy', 'Johannes Kepler', 'Nicolas Copernicus'], 
            'answer': 'Nicolas Copernicus',
            'description': 'Nicolas Copernicus proposed the heliocentric model, where the Sun is at the center and the planets orbit around it.'
        },
        {
            'question': 'What is the primary process by which stars generate energy?',
            'options': ['Nuclear fission', 'Electromagnetic induction', 'Chemical combustion', 'Nuclear fusion'], 
            'answer': 'Nuclear fusion',
            'description': 'Stars, like our Sun, primarily generate energy through the process of nuclear fusion where hydrogen atoms fuse to form helium.'
        }
    ],
    # Level 17
    [
        {
            'question': 'Which protein structure is determined by the sequence of amino acids?',
            'options': ['Primary structure', 'Secondary structure', 'Tertiary structure', 'Quaternary structure'], 
            'answer': 'Primary structure',
            'description': 'The primary structure of a protein refers to the sequence of amino acids in the polypeptide chain.'
        },
        {
            'question': 'Which of these is a fundamental interaction that doesn\'t have a mediating particle associated with it in the current Standard Model of particle physics?',
            'options': ['Electromagnetic force', 'Weak nuclear force', 'Strong nuclear force', 'Gravity'], 
            'answer': 'Gravity',
            'description': 'While other forces have mediating particles (like photons for electromagnetism), gravity does not have an established mediating particle in the Standard Model.'
        },
        {
            'question': 'In the realm of quantum mechanics, which principle asserts that certain pairs of physical properties cannot be simultaneously measured with arbitrary precision?',
            'options': ['Pauli Exclusion Principle', 'Heisenberg Uncertainty Principle', 'Schrodinger\'s Cat Paradox', 'Superposition Principle'], 
            'answer': 'Heisenberg Uncertainty Principle',
            'description': 'The Heisenberg Uncertainty Principle states that certain pairs of properties (e.g., position and momentum) cannot be precisely measured simultaneously.'
        },
        {
            'question': 'Which number, when raised to the power of itself, equals a given number?',
            'options': ['Logarithm', 'Exponential', 'Derivative', 'Lambert W function'], 
            'answer': 'Lambert W function',
            'description': 'The Lambert W function, also known as the product logarithm, returns the number which when raised to its own power equals a given number.'
        },
        {
            'question': 'Which mathematical conjecture, unsolved for centuries and relating to prime numbers, was proven by Andrew Wiles in 1994?',
            'options': ['Goldbach Conjecture', 'Poincare Conjecture', 'Fermat\'s Last Theorem', 'Riemann Hypothesis'], 
            'answer': 'Fermat\'s Last Theorem',
            'description': 'Fermat\'s Last Theorem, which remained unproven for over 350 years, was eventually proven by Andrew Wiles in 1994.'
        },
        {
            'question': 'Which physicist is best known for his theory of electromagnetism?',
            'options': ['Albert Einstein', 'Niels Bohr', 'James Clerk Maxwell', 'Ernest Rutherford'], 
            'answer': 'James Clerk Maxwell',
            'description': 'James Clerk Maxwell is best known for formulating Maxwell\'s equations, which describe the behavior of electric and magnetic fields.'
        },
        {
            'question': 'Which area of mathematics deals primarily with the properties and relations of sets, especially those of a more abstract nature?',
            'options': ['Topology', 'Calculus', 'Geometry', 'Algebra'], 
            'answer': 'Topology',
            'description': 'Topology is the mathematical study of the properties of space that are preserved under continuous transformations, such as stretching and bending.'
        },
        {
            'question': 'In the domain of chemistry, what does the term "chirality" refer to?',
            'options': ['Ability to conduct electricity', 'Change in temperature with pressure', 'Non-superimposable mirror images', 'Chemical reactivity with water'], 
            'answer': 'Non-superimposable mirror images',
            'description': 'Chirality refers to molecules that are mirror images of each other but cannot be superimposed. These are also known as "optical isomers".'
        },
        {
            'question': 'Which mathematical theorem provides a relationship between the sides of a right triangle?',
            'options': ['Pythagorean theorem', 'Binomial theorem', 'Taylor\'s theorem', 'Central limit theorem'], 
            'answer': 'Pythagorean theorem',
            'description': 'The Pythagorean theorem states that in a right triangle, the square of the length of the hypotenuse is equal to the sum of the squares of the lengths of the other two sides.'
        },
        {
            'question': 'What concept in thermodynamics postulates that entropy of an isolated system always increases?',
            'options': ['First law of thermodynamics', 'Second law of thermodynamics', 'Zeroth law of thermodynamics', 'Third law of thermodynamics'], 
            'answer': 'Second law of thermodynamics',
            'description': 'The second law of thermodynamics states that the entropy of an isolated system not in equilibrium will tend to increase over time.'
        }
    ]
]